Guide to the Phyllis Chesler Papers, 1968-2003 RL.00221
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series, 1969-1988 and undated
  - Women and Madness Subseries, 1969-1980 (bulk 1969-1971)
    - Audiocassettes
      - Debbie, II - Mental Asylum (Box W8)
      - Denise (Box W8)
      - Doris (Box W8)
      - Doris (Box W8)
      - Doris - Sarah - Myrna (Box W8)
      - Dorothy R. - feminist (Box W8)
      - Dr. K. - David A., III (Box W8)
      - Ellen B. - Lesbian (2 audiocassettes) (Box W8)
      - Ellen R. - Third World (Box W8)
      - Feminist in Theory (Box W8)
      - Helen - Feminist (Box W8)
      - Incest - Sex with Therapist (Box W8)
      - Iris - Liz (Box W8)
      - Karen - Third world (Box W8)
      - Karen (Box W8)
      - Laura M., I-II (Box W8)
      - Lee R.'s Law Suit (Box W8)
      - Lila K. (2 audiocassettes) (Box W8)
      - Liz (Box W8)
      - Lynn B. - Sex w/ Therapist (Box W8)
      - Margaret (2 audiocassettes) (Box W8)
      - Marie C. - Mental Asylum (Box W8)
      - Marya (Box W8)
      - Minda (2 audiocassettes) (Box W8)
      - Muriel (Box W8)
      - Muriel, III-IV (Box W8)
      - Myra (Box W8)
      - Myrna, II (Box W8)
      - Nancy (Box W8)
      - Nancy L. (Box W8)
      - Owen R. (Box W8)
      - Pamela G. - feminist (2 audiocassettes) (Box W8)
      - Paula K. (Box W8)
      - Renee - Sex with Therapist (Box W8)
      - Rochelle III (Box W8)
      - Rose - lesbian (Box W8)
      - Sonia (Box W8)
      - Tamar (Box W8)
      - Tamar, III - IV (Box W8)
      - Thelma I. (Box W8)
      - Tina (Box W8)
      - Unidentified Audiocassette (Box W8)
    - Volumes (Box W9)
      Early edition of Women and Madness and two proof editions with substantial corrections and alterations.
      - Women and Madness, Doubleday, 1972 (Box W9)
      - Women and Madness, (proof copy) Doubleday, 1972 (Box W9)
      - Women and Madness, (proof copy) Doubleday, 1972 (Box W9)
  - Women, Money and Power subseries, 1974-1976 and undated
    The Women and Madness Subseries, 1969-1980, (bulk 1969-1971) is composed of interview transcripts, research files, audiocassettes, and chapter drafts.
    - Interview Transcripts (Box W10)
      Interview transcripts are labeled with the name of the person interviewed and are arranged alphabetically.
      - Employed Widow, 1974 (Box W10)
      - F., Brenda (Box W10)
      - H., Alice, 1974 (Box W10)
      - J., Janet and Anne H., 1974 (Box W10)
      - K., Marlene (Box W10)
      - M., Madelene (Box W10)
      - P., Eileen (Box W10)
      - S., Dolores, 1974 (Box W10)
      - S., Muriel, 1974 (Box W10)
      - T., Jane, 1974 (Box W10)
      - Laura X, 1974 (Box W10)
      - Misc. (Box W10)
      - Money and Power Transcript Interviews (Box W10)
      - Unidentified Transcript (Box W10)
      - Summary of Interviews (Box W10)
    - Research Files
      Research files primarily examine female psychology, attitudes to work, power, successful women, and attitudes toward money; they are arranged alphabetically.
      - Achievement (Box W10)
      - Achievement, Carbon (Box W10)
      - Agenda, Completed, In Progress (Box W10)
      - Anxieties of Inflation (Box W10)
      - Attitudes about Work (Box W10)
      - Attitudes to Money (Box W10)
      - Ayn Rand: The Fountainhead (Box W10)
      - Beauty (3 folders) (Box W10)
      - Beauty Carbons (Box W10)
      - Behavior and Psychology of Women In and Out of Home (Box W10)
      - Behavior at Work (Box W10)
      - Bell, Carolyn Shaw (Box W10)
      - Biographies of Women (Box W10)
      - Birmingham, Stephen: "The Right People," 1958 (Box W10)
      - Brooklyn College of Pharmacy (Box W10)
      - Bureau of Labor Statistics Consumption (Box W10)
      - Chapter Outline, Jan., 1975 (Box W10)
      - Charts: Women at Financial Top, Jan., 1975 (Box W10)
      - Chesler and Goodman Letters (Box W10)
      - Consumer Expenditures and Income: Survey Guidelines (Box W10)
      - Contacts: Money Book (Box W10)
      - Corporate Wives: Corporate Casualties? (Box W10)
      - Clippings, 1969-1975 (Box W11)
      - Correspondence (Box W11)
      - Cosmetic Research (Box W11)
      - Cosmetics: Clothing (Box W11)
      - C.V. Materials (Box W11)
      - Dictated (Box W11)
      - Dictated, July 10-17 (Box W11)
      - Discussion of Power (Box W11)
      - Double Standard in Practice (Box W11)
      - Dutton (Publisher) (Box W11)
      - Earlier Versions of Money and Women Book (Box W11)
      - Economic Education Bulletin (Box W11)
      - Economic Facts of Life (Box W11)
      - Economics of Female Beauty (Box W11)
      - Economics of Sex (Box W11)
      - Emily Goodman (Box W11)
      - Emily's Work (Box W11)
      - Exceptional Women (Box W11)
      - Female Attitudes to Money (Box W11)
      - Female Beauty (Box W11)
      - Female Physical Body (Box W11)
      - Female Psychology (Box W11)
      - Feminism (Box W11)
      - Financial Top (4 folders) (Box W11)
      - Final Book Outline (Box W11)
      - Form Letter Originals (Box W11)
      - Fortune, 1973 (Box W12)
      - Fortune Top 10 Women (Box W12)
      - Fortune Surveys (Box W12)
      - Foundations (Box W12)
      - Full Employment--For Whom? (Box W12)
      - Greene, Helene, 1974 (Box W12)
      - Group Therapy Notes (Box W12)
      - Height Studies (Box W12)
      - High Status, Affluent Women (Box W12)
      - Household Help Wanted (Box W12)
      - How to Bring Up a Child (Box W12)
      - Institute for Social Research, University of Michigan (Box W12)
      - The Interview (Box W12)
      - Interview Preparation (Box W12)
      - Interviews, Carbons: Employed Widow, Secretary (Box W12)
      - Interviews: Livingston, Levy; Berry, Walters (Box W12)
      - Introduction (Box W12)
      - Introduction, Draft (Box W12)
      - Introduction Including Options (Box W12)
      - Leftovers (Box W12)
      - Magazine Articles (Box W12)
      - Manufacturing (Box W12)
      - Marriage and Money (Box W12)
      - Marriage and Motherhood (Box W12)
      - Marriage and Motherhood Job Description (Box W12)
      - Metropolitan Clinical Internship (Box W12)
      - Minor Study #1 (Box W12)
      - Miscellaneous (Box W12)
      - The Mod Donne Reviews (Box W12)
      - Money Book Correspondence (Box W12)
      - Money Book: Requests for Info (Box W12)
      - Money Contacts Pending (Box W12)
      - Money Maxims (Box W12)
      - Money Problems (Box W12)
      - Moneysworth (Box W12)
      - Mothers (Box W12)
      - Mothers as Workers, Secretaries (Box W12)
      - Mothers as Workers, Secretaries Carbon (Box W12)
      - Mothers as Workers, Secretaries Interviews (Box W12)
      - Myth and Women (Box W12)
      - New York State College of Human Ecology (Box W12)
      - Non-market Components of National Income (Box W12)
      - Non-Payoff (Box W12)
      - Obituary Pages (Box W12)
      - Organizing Outlines (Box W12)
      - Outline, 1975 (Box W12)
      - Outline and Organization (Box W12)
      - Outline: Leftovers from Beauty (Box W12)
      - Parental Influence in Successful Women (Box W12)
      - Parenting and Success (Box W12)
      - Parenting of Non-Ordinary Women (Box W12)
      - Physicality (Box W12)
      - Physicality: Body Image (Box W12)
      - P.O.N.Y.--Jean Powell (Box W12)
      - Power (Box W12)
      - Prices and Living Conditions (Box W12)
      - Prisons and Crime (Box W12)
      - Psychodynamics of Survival (Box W13)
      - Psycho-Economics of Female Beauty (Box W13)
      - Psycho-Economics of Women at Wage Labor (Box W13)
      - Psychology and Economics of Volunteer Work (Box W13)
      - Psychology of Women (Box W13)
      - Publicity: Avon (Box W13)
      - Publicity: Bantam (Box W13)
      - Quotes (Box W13)
      - Quotes for Women and Money (Box W13)
      - Ramparts (Box W13)
      - Research Files (Box W13)
      - Rich Ladies and Volunteerism (Box W13)
      - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Box W13)
      - Science: A Process Approach (Box W13)
      - Sexual Economics (Box W13)
      - Statistics (Box W13)
      - Stock Market Cosmetics (Box W13)
      - Studies Done for this Book (Box W13)
      - Survival Tactics of Successful Women (Box W13)
      - The Token Woman (Box W13)
      - To Dictate (Box W13)
      - Varieties of Power (Box W13)
      - Volunteerism (3 folders) (Box W13)
      - Wage Labor (Box W13)
      - Wealthy Women in America (Box W13)
      - Wealthy Women in America, Drafts 2 and 3 (Box W13)
      - Welfare History (Box W13)
      - Wives/Daughters of Wealth (Box W13)
      - Wives/Daughters of Wealth, Carbon (Box W13)
      - Women at Work (Box W13)
      - Women on Money (Box W13)
      - Women, Revolution, Feminism (Box W13)
      - Work (Box W13)
      - Work and Attitudes to Work (Box W13)
      - Working (Box W13)
      - Working Mothers (Box W14)
      - Working Women (Box W14)
      - "Working" Chapter, New (Box W14)
      - Writing for First or Last Chapter (Box W14)
      - W. W. Norton and Co. (Box W14)
    - Audiocassettes
      Audiocassettes are arranged chronologically, and are labeled according to the person interviewed, the site of the interview, or the main subject of the interview. Undated materials are listed last.
      - 1974, March 28, Chasen, Sex Role Stereotypes (Box W14)
      - 1974, April 14, Martha and Pete W. (Box W14)
      - 1974, April 18, Women Counseling Center (Box W14)
      - 1974, April 18, Women Counseling Center (Box W14)
      - 1974, April 18, Women Counseling Center (Box W14)
      - 1974, April 19, Meeting with Cooper (Box W14)
      - 1974, May 2, Careers (Box W14)
      - 1974, May 2, Pay for Motherhood/Self-Defense (Box W14)
      - 1974, May 3, Pots, Pornography/ Men as Passive/ Fellatio in Pornography (Box W14)
      - 1974, May 3, Sexual Deviance (Box W14)
      - 1974, May 9, Class #11 (Box W14)
      - 1974, May 9, Class #11 (Box W14)
      - 1974, May 16, Class #12 (Box W14)
      - 1974, May 23, Class #13 Strategies for Power (Box W14)
      - 1974, May 28, Jean Powell (Box W14)
      - 1974, May 28, My After Comments: Jean Powell (Box W14)
      - 1974, May 31, Alice H. (Box W14)
      - 1974, June 5, Muriel S. (Box W14)
      - 1974, June 5, Muriel S. (Box W14)
      - 1974, June 6, Jane T. (Box W14)
      - 1974, June 7, Brenda F. (Box W14)
      - 1974, June 11, Management Women: Anne H. and Janet J. (Box W14)
      - 1974, June 11, Anne H. and Janet J. (Box W14)
      - 1974, June 14, Dolores S. (Box W14)
      - 1974, June 14, Dolores S. (Box W14)
      - 1974, June 22, Employed Widow (Box W14)
      - 1974, June 22, Employed Widow (Box W14)
      - 1974, June 23, Madelene M.: Women's Bank (Box W14)
      - 1974, June 23, Shelly C.: Executive Women (Box W14)
      - 1974, June 24, Marlene K.: WAA (Box W14)
      - 1974, June 26, Eileen P., Madelene M.: Women's Bank (Box W14)
      - 1974, June, J.T. (Box W14)
      - 1974, July 27, Pell C. (Box W14)
      - 1974, Counseling Center (Box W14)
      - 1974, Richmond Counseling Center (Box W14)
      - 1974, Richmond Counseling Center (Box W14)
      - 1975, February 27, Phyllis Explains Her Contracts (Box W14)
      - 1975, March 11, Me at Kiryat/ Pat (Box W14)
      - 1975, March 11, David S. (Box W14)
      - N.d., ACH/Women CEO (Box W14)
      - N.d., Del G. (Box W14)
      - N.d., Del G. (Box W14)
      - N.d., Essay/Pieta (Box W14)
      - N.d., Judith M. (Box W14)
      - N.d., Judith M. (Box W14)
      - N.d., Notes to Wm. (Box W14)
      - N.d., Owl and Me (Box W14)
      - N.d., Piercy, Marge: Radio Free People (Box W14)
      - N.d., Sylvia P. (Box W14)
      - N.d., Warrior Women, Menarchy, Legendary Amazons (Box W14)
      - N.d., Untitled (Box W14)
      - N.d., Untitled (Box W14)
    - Chapter Drafts (Box W15)
      - Introduction (Box W15)
      - Chapter 1 (2 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 2 (4 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 3 (2 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 4 (4 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 5 (4 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 6 (3 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 7 (3 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 8 (3 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 9 (3 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 10 (2 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 11 (2 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 12 (2 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 13 (2 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 14 (3 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 15 (2 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 16 (3 folders) (Box W15)
      - Chapter 17 (3 folders) (Box W15)
      - Bibliography (2 folders) (Box W15)
      - Original (2 folders) (Box W15)
      - Copy, 179 Pages (Box W15)
  - About Men subseries, 1970-1979, bulk 1974-1978
    This subseries is divided into four sections: Research Files, Audiocassettes and Tapes, Illustrations, and Typescripts. Chesler's folder titles have been retained throughout.
    - Research Files, 1971-1979, bulk 1973-1975.
      Predominantly consists of clippings and photocopies of articles, but also includes notes, bibliographies, and transcripts of interviews on male and female psychology, parent-child relations, sex roles, and sexual violence among other subjects. Arranged in alphabetical order by subject. Some audiocassettes and reel-to-reel tapes of various interviews by Chesler are housed at the end of this subseries.
      - About Men: Advertisement and Reviews (Box W16)
      - About Men Grant Proposal (Box W16)
      - Adolescence (Box W16)
      - Alcoholism (Box W16)
      - American Presidents: Extra men - CB (Box W16)
      - Animal Studies (Box W16)
      - Anti-Feminist Writings Violence ca. 1974 (Box W16)
      - Bibliographic Work/Research in Progress: Shirley P., James S., Norman, ca. 1974 (Box W16)
      - Bibliography -- Mainly women ca. 1974 (Box W16)
      - Bibliography -- Male Psychology Books (Box W16)
      - Bibliography: Men, July 1974 (Box W16)
      - For Bibliography (4 folders) (Box W16)
      - Biological or Medical Studies (Box W16)
      - Birth Order (Box W16)
      - Black Psychology, Behavior (2 folders) (Box W16)
      - Body Image (Box W16)
      - Brothers (Box W16)
      - Business (Box W16)
      - Cheating Science, Aug. 20, 1974 (Box W16)
      - Child Abuse (Box W16)
      - Child Custody (Box W16)
      - Child Rearing: Mother-child, Family Therapy (Box W16)
      - Child Support (Box W16)
      - Congress Women (Box W16)
      - Contemporary Feminists (Box W16)
      - Discrimination (Box W16)
      - Divorced Men (Box W16)
      - Experiments on People (Box W16)
      - Family (Box W16)
      - The Famous Ladies (Box W16)
      - Famous Men (Box W16)
      - 30 Famous Men (current biographies) (Box W16)
      - Famous Women (2 folders) (Box W16)
      - 30 Famous Women: Variables from Current Biographies (Box W16)
      - Fashion (Box W16)
      - Fathers and Sons (Box W16)
      - "Fathers Killing Sons" (Box W16)
      - Feminists (Box W16)
      - Film (Box W16)
      - Film Festival Material (Box W16)
      - Film Panel, ca. 1975 (3 folders) (Box W16)
      - Gambling (Box W16)
      - Group Behavior (Box W16)
      - Heightism, ca. 1971 (Box W16)
      - Hero - Mythology - Greek; money as success, ca. 1974 (Box W17)
      - Hero - Warrior - money - success (Box W17)
      - Heroes (Box W17)
      - Heroes? (Box W17)
      - Homosexuality -- Male: Gay liberation (Box W17)
      - Hostility to Women (Box W17)
      - Housewives (Box W17)
      - Incest (Box W17)
      - Infanticide -- Father Killing Sons, ca. 1974 (Box W17)
      - Infanticides (Box W17)
      - Intellectual Backlash, ca. 1974 (Box W17)
      - Interview, July 23, 1973 (Box W17)
      - Interview Questions (Box W17)
      - Interview with John, undated (Box W17)
      - Interview with Walter, May 28, 1974 (Box W17)
      - Interview with Michael (Box W17)
      - Interviews (4 folders) (Box W17)
      - "The Jocasta Complex: Mothering and Genius" (Box W17)
      - Joplin Review for the Washington Post (Box W17)
      - Koch Responses (Women of Public Achievement) (Box W17)
      - Lesbianism (Box W17)
      - Letter to Men's Anthology Collective, Feb. 25, 1974 (Box W17)
      - Male Adult -- Male Adult Violence, ca. June 1974 (Box W17)
      - Male American Nobel Prize Winners - Literature, Physiology, and Medicine, ca. 1972 (Box W17)
      - "Male Attitude to Motherhood" (Box W17)
      - Male as warrior -- class, ca. 1974 (Box W17)
      - Male Groups (Box W17)
      - Male Images: Additional Writings to be Added (Box W17)
      - Male Liberation Conference Arkansas, April 25 to 28, 1974 (Box W17)
      - Male Liberation Conference, March 1974 (Box W17)
      - Male Literature, 1974 (Box W17)
      - Male - Male Violence: Psychiatry, ca. 1973 (Box W17)
      - Male Maternity (Box W17)
      - Male Physicality and Psychology (Box W17)
      - Male Presidents (Box W17)
      - Male Psychology (Box W17)
      - Male Revolution, Oct. 7, 1974 (Box W17)
      - Male Violence (Box W17)
      - Male Violence -- Father Beating Sons, 1972 (Box W17)
      - Male Violence -- Fratricide, May 8, 1974 (Box W17)
      - Male Violence -- Patricide -- Sons Beating Fathers (Symbolic Also), ca. 1975 (Box W17)
      - "Matriarch" (Box W17)
      - Men Prisoners, ca. 1974 (Box W17)
      - Men: Resources: "Anger to father..." (Box W17)
      - Men: Resources: "Men and War" (Box W17)
      - Men: Resources: Hero (Box W17)
      - Men - To Interview (Box W17)
      - Mental Asylums, 1974 (Box W17)
      - Metromedia, Jan. 4, 1979 (Box W17)
      - Money (Box W17)
      - Money and Men (Box W17)
      - Money: Psychoanalytic Int. (Box W17)
      - Mothers and Sons, 9/4/75 (Box W17)
      - Mothers and Sons, ca. 1975 (Box W17)
      - Mothers and Sons -- Phallic Sexuality (discards), ca. 1977 (Box W17)
      - Natality, Nov. 6, 1974 (Box W18)
      - Natality, Child Growth (Box W18)
      - Newspaper Clippings (Box W18)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1977 (Box W18)
      - Newspaper Clippings Battered Wives (Box W18)
      - Newspaper Clippings "Brothers and Brothers" (Box W18)
      - Newspaper Clippings "Fathers against Sons, Sons against Fathers" (Box W18)
      - Newspaper Clippings "Fathers Killing Sons" (Box W18)
      - Newspaper Clippings "Fathers Killing Sons" (Box W18)
      - Newspaper Clippings "Fathers Killing Sons" (Box W18)
      - Newspaper Clippings "Male Uterus-Envy" (Box W18)
      - Newspaper Clippings "Sons against Mothers" (Box W18)
      - Newspaper Clippings "Sons Killing Fathers," 1973 to 1976 (Box W18)
      - Newspaper Clippings "Sons: Practicing" (Box W18)
      - Newspaper Clippings "World Expressions" (Box W18)
      - Nobel Prize Men, ca. 1974 (Box W18)
      - Non-continuity -- Eve and Phyllis -- "Versions" (2 folders) (Box W18)
      - Norman and Research, ca. 1974 (Box W18)
      - Norman: Psychoanalytic (Box W18)
      - Note to Women's Movement (2 folders) (Box W18)
      - Notes for Essay (Box W18)
      - Op-Ed (Box W18)
      - Op-Ed Notes (Box W18)
      - Paternity Leave, Feb. 14, 1974 (Box W18)
      - Political Sadism -- General Calamity, ca. 1970 (Box W18)
      - Politicians and Sex, Oct. 11, 1974 (Box W18)
      - Pornography, ca. 1974 (Box W18)
      - Preface (Box W18)
      - Preface Materials (Discarded) (Box W18)
      - Principal Religions (Box W18)
      - Prostitution, July 10, 1974 (Box W18)
      - Psychotherapy/Psychology (Box W18)
      - Racism, June 2, 1975 (Box W18)
      - Rape (Box W18)
      - Rape, ca. 1975 (2 folders) (Box W18)
      - Readings Series (3 folders) (Box W18)
      - Religion and Sex (Box W18)
      - Reprint Regrets and Answers (Box W18)
      - Research on Males, Bibliography, Articles and Books (Box W18)
      - Section III: "Male Realities" (Box W18)
      - Selective Inattention (Box W18)
      - Sex and Money, Nov. 7, 1974 (Box W18)
      - Sex, ca. 1974 (Box W18)
      - Sex Roles, ca. 1973 (Box W18)
      - Sex Roles: Male-Changing, Oct. 16, 1974 (Box W18)
      - Sex Slaying, Sept. 3, 1974 (Box W18)
      - Sex-role Stereotypes, ca. 1975 (2 folders) (Box W18)
      - Sex-role Stereotyping Childhood, ca. 1974 (Box W18)
      - Sexes -- Battle/War of, ca. 1974 (Box W18)
      - Sexuality, ca. 1974 (Box W18)
      - Singles and Divorced, ca. 1974 (Box W18)
      - Sociological Papers, 1975 to 1976 (Box W19)
      - "Sons Against Mothers" (Box W19)
      - Sons Practicing (Box W19)
      - Success--Male (Box W19)
      - To Be Dictated (Box W19)
      - Transvestite and Transsexual, ca. 1974 (Box W19)
      - Unemployment, Oct. 20, 1974 (Box W19)
      - "Untying the Family" (Box W19)
      - Veterans, ca. March 1974 (Box W19)
      - Violence: Aggression, ca. 1971 (Box W19)
      - Violence: Male (General), ca. 1974 (Box W19)
      - Violence: Male Delinquency, ca. 1973 (Box W19)
      - Warriors, Money, Fathers and, ca. 1975 (Box W19)
      - "Warriors:" Nationalism (Box W19)
      - Warrior - Successful Men - Money; Male-Male Violence, Summer 1974 (Box W19)
      - Women and Drugs (Box W19)
      - Women's Liberation, ca. 1974 (Box W19)
      - Women's Movement: Men's Reaction, ca. 1971 (Box W19)
      - Women -- Nobel Prize (Box W19)
      - Women in Arts, ca. Sept. 1974 (Box W19)
      - Women in Sports (Box W19)
      - Work, ca. 1974 (Box W19)
      - Work Houses: Victorian Society/Welfare, Oct. 16, 1974 (Box W19)
    - Audiocassettes and Tapes, 1974-1975
      Audiocassettes and reel-to-reel tapes of various interviews by Chesler, arranged chronologically. Undated materials appear at the end.
      - Alcoholism, Addiction, May 10, 1974 (1/2 mil reel-to-reel tape) (Box W19)
      - Male Impotence, June 9, 1974 (audiocassette) (Box W19)
      - Male Menopause, June, 1974 (audiocassette) (Box W19)
      - March 8, 1974 (1/2 mil reel-to-reel tape) (Box W19)
      - Side 2--Crime and Drug Addiction, April 14, ca. 1974 (1/2 mil reel-to-reel tape) (Box W19)
      - Walter, May 23, 1975 (audiocassette) (Box W19)
      - Untitled, undated (6.35mm reel-to-reel tape) (Box W19)
    - Illustrations, ca. 1977
      Photographs, photocopies, lists, captions, and permissions for illustrations for About Men. Includes illustrations and captions used in the book as well as those that were discarded. Arranged in alphabetical order.
      - Captions (discards) (Box W19)
      - Discarded Captions (Box W19)
      - Extra Photos -- Plates (Box W19)
      - L., Eli, "Oedipal" (Box W19)
      - Male Images: Photographs and Captions (Box W19)
      - Male Images: Photographs and Captions, Feb. 6, 1977 (Box W19)
      - Partial List of Plates (pictures) (Box W19)
      - Permissions (discards), Feb. 22, 197? (Box W19)
      - Photocopied Plates (not used) (Box W19)
      - Photographs (Box W19)
      - Photographs (Box W19)
      - Photos and Captions (Box W19)
      - Pictures (Box W19)
      - Pictures (discarded or duplicated) (Box W19)
      - Pictures (discards) (Box W19)
      - Pictures (dropped) (Box W19)
      - Pictures (unused) (Box W19)
      - Pictures, "The Life of Jesse" (Box W19)
      - Pictures, Captions (Box W20)
      - Pictures, Images (Box W20)
      - Pictures, Permissions (Box W20)
      - Re-Written Captions, March 30, 1977 (Box W20)
      - Untitled (Box W20)
    - Typescripts, 1971-1979, bulk 1975-1978
      Typescripts and some manuscript notes of individual chapters; complete typescript drafts of the book. Includes early versions of the book under the title Lovers and Warriors. Original folder titles, which roughly parallel chapter titles in the published work, have been retained. Original order of folders has been retained. Complete typescripts and proofs are at the end of the subseries.
      - Section I, Dec. 29, 1976 (Box W20)
      - ca. 1977 (4 folders) (Box W20)
      - Autobiographical Portraits, March 16, 1977 (2 folders) (Box W20)
      - Epilogue (Box W20)
      - "Fathers and Sons," "Talking to Men about Sex," "Brothers" (Box W20)
      - Part II: Male Realities: Autobiographical Portraits, 1962 to 1971 (Box W20)